## Michael Jorge H. Perez

San Francisco, CA • (415) 606-0253 • mjhperez@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mikeyjperez • github.com/Ochaart

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front End: JavaScript (ES6+), React, jQuery, Babel / Webpack, HTML5, CSS

Back-end: MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, RESTAPI, Nginx

Deployment/Testing: Docker, AWS (EC2, S3), New Relic, Jest/Enzyme, Mocha/Chai, Loader.io, K6, Git

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING APPLICATIONS**

## Catwalk | Front-End Software Engineer

- Architected the React front-end service of two photo carousels and pop-up modal backed with RESTful API backend.
- Created seamless user experience through dynamic client-side routing using React Router that empowered users to browse through all retail items served by product API server.

### System Design Capstone | Back-End Software Engineer

- Scaled and designed multi-layer backend system that can handle 500 rps to 4,000 rps using load balancing through NGINX.
- Optimized query design in SQL via joins and subqueries to reduce database response time from 30ms to 4ms. **StichSaver Web Application** | Front-End Software Engineer
- Built the user page interface which displayed up to 5 vertical carousels representing created, purchased, favorited, in progress and completed patterns.
- Created optimized experience for new and existing users integrating backend Authentication service and ContextAPI to conditionally render logged in and non-logged in landing pages.
- Increased API performance by debouncing client interactions on frequently used elements.
- Dynamically rendered pop-up modal at desired location based on click event clientX and clientY and factoring in scrolling offset.

#### **CAREER HIGHLIGHTS**

# SPORT BOX Bar and Restaurant Co-Founder, CFO and COO

Mazatlán, Mexico

April 2020-Oct 2020

Oversaw the launch of the establishment by providing finance, accounting, purchasing, and operations support.

InterContinental Hotels
Senior | Sales Manager, Group Sales
Assistant Front Office Manager
Front desk Supervisor

San Francisco, CA Sep 2016 – Apr 2020 Feb 2015 - Sep 2016 Sep 2014 - Feb 2015

Specialized in pharmaceutical and large association markets to sell room blocks, meeting space, and catering for two area hotels. In prior positions, supervised 30 employees in front office operations, achieving quality service through training and incentive programs. Experienced in concierge, marketing, and public relations. Gave tours, designed promotional materials, and networked, amassing more than 300 contacts with businesses in the city and surpassed revenue targets every quarter.

#### Accomplishments:

 Recognized by the supervisor for making immediate impact in industry that was difficult to penetrate. Awards included: Marketing Star of the Quarter, 2019; Above and Beyond, 2018, and Sales Manager of the Quarter, 2018

### **TRAINING and EDUCATION**

Advanced Software Engineering Immersive, Hack Reactor, San Francisco 2021 B.S., International Hospitality Management, Enderun College, Manila, Philippines, 2010.

- Dean's List and merit scholarships, 2006-2010; cum laude.
- Les Roches Certificate of Recognition

Hotel and Restaurant Institution Management, College of Saint Benilde, Manila, Philippines, 2004-2005

LANGUAGES: Filipino (Tagalog), fluent

HOBBIES: Cooking, eating (foodie), gaming, pool, traveling, stock marketing investing, and running.